Rituals, beliefs, and myths in this series are a work of fiction and in no regard refer to religions or faiths of any certain cultures.
He did not lie to you, Pete.
He lied to us.
Your sister is awake now.
Shit!
Niran?
May your life spirit drift away
and be lost for all eternity,
There has to be a way to bring him back.
The only person who can save Niran
is you.
(Once,)
(Zhuangzi dreamed he was a butterfly,)
(flitting and fluttering happily about.)
(The butterfly did not have a clue
that he was Zhuangzi.)
(But when Zhuangzi opened his eyes,)
(aware of who he was,)
(Zhuangzi was suddenly
uncertain of what he was.)
(Was he Zhuangzi who dreamed
he was a butterfly,)
(or a butterfly who dreamed
he spent his whole life as Zhuangzi?)
Oh, hey, Niran.
After we defeat Qi Rong,
what are you going to do next?
I’d probably continue defeating yao
if someone hires me.
No, that’s not what I meant.
Don’t you have dreams?
You know, like, grand plans
you have for your life?
Nope.
Why?
You do?
Actually I think…
I might go back to college.
I’ve always wanted to do that,
but never had the courage to.
But I realized now
that if I don’t do it,
my life wouldn’t mean a thing.
That’s nice.
I still don’t know what I want to do, though.
There’s gotta be something.
I’m sure you’ll know soon.
A guy like you wasn’t born
to just coast through life.
How about this?
Why don’t you help me think
what kind of thing
a guy like me should do?
Sure thing.
I’m not as smart as you.
But I’ll do my best to help you.
Alright.
Cheers.
Okay.
(You have to look for him
in the Life Spirit Realm.)
SUN, WINDOW, RITUAL ALTAR
BIG MIRROR (REFLECT YOUR BACK)
MONKEY AND TIGER STUFFIES
AS MEDIUMS
DOOR
(The silver lining in this situation is that
Niran’s soul is bound to yours.)
(That thread is the thing that will help you.)
(The Life Spirit Realm is a land that
does not exist under heaven, )
(nor above earth.)
(If one must define it, it is comparable
to the reflection in a mirror.)
(That world has everything to offer,)
(except the truth.)
(To enter that world, there are
three things you need to do.)
First, the Life Spirit Realm is vast
and moves as fast as one’s thoughts.
You need to keep in mind
what you’re there for.
Do not lose your focus.
Second, Niran enters
that world unknowingly.
Once you find him, you need to do
whatever it takes for him to trust you,
and let you guide him back.
Third, a human’s life spirit can
survive without its body for a month,
in that world, it is only eight hours.
You have to leave within eight hours,
otherwise, you will be stuck there
and, eventually, devoured by it.
May the power of heaven and earth
bring me into the Life Spirit Realm
to look for Niran.
Oh?
What are you doing here?
What…
Well, you know—
Come down to breakfast.
Mom asked me to get you.
What?
Mom?
I’m gaining weight, Dad.
Oh, not at all.
This looks good, though.
And it’s good, too.
What are you two talking about?
Come on and sit down, honey.
Oh, this is really good.
Oh?
Pete.
Let’s have breakfast, dear.
It’s 9 o’clock.
You think there’s going
to be traffic, honey?
I told you to wake Pete up earlier.
Your brother was just done
with his tournament.
I just thought we could
let him rest a little longer.
Come on, you two.
We’ll be fine even if there’s traffic.
It’s best to take it easy
when taking a trip, right, Pete?
Yes.
You should have breakfast.
Breakfast is super good today.
Let’s share this with your brother.
Pete, just eat your breakfast already
so we can leave.
I made your favorite minced pork, Ploy.
You could have given me more, Mom.
You can always ask for seconds, dear.
You’re the best.
Eat well, Pete.
I have something to tell you.
Our hotel is right on the beach.
Your feet will touch the ocean
the moment you open the door.
Really?
You wanna go for a swim
with your old man?
Of course.
Alright, Pete?
Don’t hold back, son.
Is that what you’re wearing
to the beach, Pete?
What type of room is it again?
VIP, of course.
Don’t you know who your old man is?
How luxurious!
PETE JIRAPAT PRUETICHAIANAN
WON FIRST GOLD IN 10 YEARS
FOR YUDO AT SEA GAMES
FIRST TROPHY FOR
HIGH SCHOOL YUDO
PETE JIRAPAT PRUETICHAIANAN
WON THAILAND’S 5TH
YOUTH YUDO CHAMPIONSHIP
Pete, are you ready, dear?
Come on.
Your dad and Ploy are waiting.
I want to be there to check in early
in case we can choose our room.
I’m sorry, Mom.
I really can’t come with you.
Hey.
What’s going on?
It’s your son.
He said he’s not coming with us.
Why not, son?
It’s been a while since our family gets
to spend time together like this.
You’re right.
It’s been a while since I last
spent time with you both.
I just hope…
I meet you again one day.
I hope we can live together,
spend time together.
take a trip together,
be happy together.
But now isn’t the right time.
I have something more important to do.
Please don’t be mad at me, you guys.
I’m sorry.
It’s okay, dear.
How could we be mad at you
for continuing to live your life?
My champion.
Where are you, Niran?
Niran?
Do I know you?
Hey.
Niran, wait.
Hear me out.
You’re not in the real world right now.
You’re in the Life Spirit Realm.
What realm?
Whatever the hell it is,
you need to come with me.
Come with you?
No way.
Why not?
Gung said I would never become Wu.
Hey.
Where are you going?
Suming School.
I’m going to train to become Wu.
Niran.
Come on.
Come back with me.
I said no.
You seriously running away just ’cause
your grandpa said one mean thing?
Are you insane?
You keep walking but do you even
know where Suming School is?
Probably up there.
Niran.
Don’t you feel that
nothing makes sense here?
You’re walking towards
you don’t even know where.
You know why?
Because this isn’t the real world.
Listen to me, Niran.
One day in the future, you will become Wu.
You just need to come back with me.
When you open your eyes, you will realize
that you already are Wu.
You don’t need to go anywhere.
Believe me.
Hurts, doesn’t it?
It’s not a dream.
Oh, you jerk.
So the getting on people’s nerves
starts young, huh?
Niran, wait!
Hey, Niran.
Wait up.
Niran, stop it.
Niran.
Hey!
Talk to me.
Niran, do you hear me?
Ow, shit.
Hey.
Niran.
Oh, idiot, look around you.
Niran, do you hear me?
Hey.
Wait.
Shit.
Hey!
Niran!
You’ve been wasting two hours.
You’ve had enough now?
You will never reach it.
I will reach it if I keep walking.
Yeah? Does that mountain seem
any closer to you, though?
It must.
I’ve been walking all this time.
No.
It’s not closer.
And I can guarantee
you will never reach it.
Stop talking nonsense.
I have to get to Suming today.
And I will become Wu.
Really?
How many times do you think
you’ve walked by this spot?
Nothing is waiting for you
at the end of the road.
Because this isn’t the path of your real life.
You’re lost in the Life Spirit Realm.
If I don’t make it to Suming School,
that means…
I’ll never become Wu.
You wanted to be Wu so badly?
What about it?
Nothing.
Then how come you don’t believe me
when I told you you’re already Wu?
Why are you running away from home
and walking to Suming School?
You got through this part of your life
for a long time now.
You know what?
I was offended by my coach
as well when I was a kid.
He said the likes of me
would never be an athlete.
But I didn’t care.
I just kept showing up to practice
again and again,
and I got into a tournament.
I won gold.
But in the end, I behaved so badly that
I got expelled from the association.
I didn’t even get a chance to turn pro.
So your coach was right?
You can say that.
But think carefully why I didn’t
become an athlete.
Was it because of what my coach said
or my own action?
Niran.
I don’t know why your grandpa said
what he said.
But what does it matter?
It’s what you choose to do and
the path you choose to walk on
that make you Wu.
Come back with me.
Come back to your real life.
Can I trust you, Pete?
Of course!
I swear you can totally freaking trust me.
Come back with me.
Wu Yong Le!
Gung!
Hey, Niran!
Ow, fuc—
Oi!
What the hell are you standing there for?
You’re in the way!
Do I know you?
It’s me, Pete.
Pete who?
I don’t know you.
I’m in a hurry.
Move away!
I’m here to get you back—Crap!
You jerk!
Can’t you get lost in the time
after we’ve met?
This could have been easier, you idiot!
(You have to leave within eight hours,)
otherwise, you will be stuck there
and, eventually, devoured by it.
‘It’?
What do you mean?
Taixu.
Also known as ‘the Eternal Void.’
Its job is to clean up life spirits that have been in the Life Spirit Realm for too long
to maintain balance in the universe.
If you don’t bring Niran back in time,
his life spirit will be wiped away
by Taixu as well.
That means his being
will disappear for eternity.
You’re impossible to defeat, huh?
You’ve evaded me 13 times.
But this time, I’ll definitely get you.
So this is the yao that caused
a blackout all through the city?
This must be another thing
you can’t get over.
That’s why you want to
come back and defeat it.
Who the hell are you?
What are you babbling?
I told you I don’t know you.
You don’t know me now.
But you will give me this necklace later.
Come back with me.
You’re just wasting your time here.
I can’t go anywhere with you.
I have a duty to fulfill here.
This is the first task I received
from the elders Wu.
If I don’t succeed,
they will never accept me my whole life.
So what?
What do you even care?
Of course I do.
I won’t let myself become an outcast.
Alright.
You jerk of a yao.
Come at me!
Stop it!
Stop trying to defeat it!
You can’t win!
Because you never defeated it in real life!
What already happened
already happened!
Why do you waste your time
thinking about it?
Just come back with me, you idiot!
You’re back.
You are an obstinate one.
A man whose compass in life
is his obstinance
will be lost forever.
What are you standing there for?
There’s plenty of seats for you to sit down.
Niran.
I don’t care if you don’t know me right now.
But you need to come back with me.
What are you saying, Pete?
Why wouldn’t I know you?
So you know why I’m here?
You’re here to get me back
to defeat Qi Rong.
Yes.
You need to come back and finish it.
There are so many people waiting for you.
Even if I don’t,
someone will defeat it.
Jia Hao.
Fei.
Or someone from the school.
You know, maybe I’m not that important.
Where are you going, then?
Dunno.
I’ll go wherever it takes me.
It’s not taking you anywhere
if you keep sitting here.
Look.
It’s devoured the entire atmosphere now.
You’re the only thing left.
No.
Everything looks normal to me.
Normal, my ass.
Don’t you see how empty it is outside?
You think that’s normal?
Is your normal different from this?
Wherever we are, whatever we do,
or whatever we surround ourselves with,
you think it matters?
You jerk, but—
Pete.
Can’t I just sit down for once?
Sure thing.
All I ask is that
if things get risky around here,
you need to let me get you out of here.
You know,
I always dreamed of
when I was a kid.
I was running after a butterfly.
Did you ever catch that butterfly
in your dream?
No.
I was the butterfly in that dream,
flying away from myself.
Niran.
Where are you going?
Don’t go!
Shit!
(You are no Wu.)
(And you never will be.)
Niran?
Niran!
Niran.
You’re still here?
Come back with me right now
before you’re…
Shit.
Shit. Shit.
Shit!
Pete.
Thank you
for coming all the way here to get me.
But I think I like it here.
What the hell are you talking about?
I want to live here.
You should go back.
No.
I’m not going back.
Not unless you’re coming with me.
Why?
The life you’ve lived and
everything that you’ve done,
you’re just going to let it
be devoured by this void?
Do you think there is more to life than this?
At least this void makes me feel nice.
Maybe…
it will even bring me closer to heaven.
No.
Not here.
Don’t you get it?
Don’t you understand it can’t be here?
You need to come back with me right now.
I don’t care if you come back
and do nothing
if you don’t want to.
You don’t want to defeat Qi Rong?
Fine.
Let’s not do that.
You don’t want to be Wu anymore?
Okay!
You don’t have to.
I don’t know where the last place
that made you happy was.
But it can’t be here, don’t you get it?
You need to come back with me!
I can’t leave you here.
Please.
I’m begging you.
Don’t do this.
You’re not alone, you know!
There are so many people waiting for you.
You’re important to people,
at least to me.
You’re very important to me.
I can’t let you go like this.
I can’t let you go.
Thank you, Pete.
Thank you.
But I think it’s too late.
No.
No!
I don’t want to leave you here.
Please.
You mean so much to everyone,
especially to me.
Don’t you understand?
Niran.
If I go with you,
I’ll become Wu, won’t I?
Yes.
You’ll be the coolest Wu ever.
You know why?
Because you’ll have me as your partner.
Will you come back with me?
JIA HAO
Hello.
How is Niran doing?
(Niran is awake now.)
What do we do now?
Here.
These belonged to Mom.
Uncle left them with me a long time ago.
This part is yours.
I kept them because I didn’t want you
to gamble them all away.
Since you quit now,
I guess you can look after them yourself.
Will you swear you won’t pawn them off?
Yeah, I swear.
I remember Mom wearing this all the time.
You only asked me to swear
not to pawn them off, right?
Here.
For leaving the hospital.
Huh?
It belonged to my Mom.
I just learned she left me something
before she died.
You gave me something of your grandpa’s.
I want to give you something of
my Mom’s in return.
I don’t know if it has power
like yours, though.
It does.
Every piece of jade that’s passed
from one hand to the next
gathers the power to protect its owner.
But are you sure you want to—
Yep.
It’s for you.
And if it has power,
I want that power to protect you.
Okay.
Hey, wait!
Why did you have to put it on that finger?
Why not?
It fits.
Forget it.
It’s no big deal.
Yeah.
Crap.
Who cares about that?
Li Puo is definitely planning something.
The power of Lord Warrior
has blanketed this entire city.
You know how to deal with Qi Rong now?
I’ll let heaven and earth decide.
Any power that defies heaven
does not last long.
At least I have you
who truly believes in me.